Take a look at this. I have four
instances of Claude code working at the
exact same time together to perform a
code review on my codebase. And this is
all thanks to the new agents teams
feature that Enthropic has built into
cloud code. And man, let me tell you, it
really does look like I'm peering into
the future of agentic engineering when I
am using it. So, we have our primary
lead agent on the lefth hand side. And
in real time, I watched it spin up each
one of these T-Mux terminals to create
these agents to collaborate on the same
task. Now, people have been doing this
sort of split pane multi-teux terminal
sort of setup for a while now. So, it's
not really new, but there are a couple
of things that make this super novel.
The first is that our primary agent, it
actually decided the team to form based
on the request that I gave it. And the
other part of this that makes it so
powerful is that under the hood, each
one of these agents is working on the
exact same task list together. So this
goes way beyond sub agents. These agents
actually talk to each other like, "Oh,
let me complete this before you work on
this." They have that kind of
communication that makes it so that we
can take this idea of parallel agents a
lot further. So in this video, I want to
cover how agent teams works with you.
It's a new experimental feature that you
have to enable. We'll talk about how to
set it up. I also really want to cover
how agent teams is different from sub
aents. A lot of people are confused by
this right now because they operate
really similarly. The main difference is
we have collaboration versus isolation.
There are pros and cons here that I want
to cover. Agent teams is really powerful
but it is not perfect. So we'll get into
that which will also lead into a
template that I have for you. This is a
command that I've built. Basically, you
can use this to give instructions for
cloud code on to how to use agent teams
better because believe it or not, even
though this is a feature built into
cloud code, it's not actually that good
at using it. And so, I'll show you how
to really take advantage of this new
feature to do some pretty incredible
things. Now, this code review
demonstration that I have for you is
just a really simple example what we can
do with agent teams. Anthropic has
published a couple of articles where
they've shown how far we can push this
idea. For example, Anthropic used 16
agents running together with this new
agent teams feature to build an entire C
compiler. And let me tell you, building
a compiler from scratch is not easy. If
you were to hire a dev team to do this,
it would probably be hundreds of
thousands of dollars. But they were able
to do it with only $20,000 in API costs,
which yes, that is still an insane
amount of money. agent teams is very
tokenheavy, which is one of the
downsides we'll talk about in a little
bit. But it's still really cool to see
how far they were able to push what is
possible with coding agents just running
together, collaborating autonomously.
They literally just threw this in
essentially a RA loop where they forced
it to write, I believe, hundreds of
thousands of lines of code to create
this. So, it's very, very incredible.
the kind of thing that they say later in
this article, there's no way that a
single agent would have been able to do
even if you were to give this whole task
to, you know, Opus 4.6, for example. All
right, so really quickly, I want to show
you how you can get your first agent
team up and running in just a couple of
minutes, and then we'll get into how
it's different from sub agents because
it is really important to understand.
So, I will have a link to this page in
the description. This is the official
guide on agent teams from Anthropic.
However, there is a lot of information
here. It's pretty overwhelming and so I
just want to break it down nice and
simple for you right now. So, the first
thing you have to do because this is an
experimental feature that is far from
perfect, trust me, you have to enable
it. And so, you can either set this
environment variable on your computer or
in just a terminal session or you can
add this to your settings.json. So, this
is one of the config files for cloud
code. You've probably worked with this
before because it's where you set things
like your MCP servers and your hooks.
And so we can set this at either the
global.cloud level or in the docloud
project directory. And so you can enable
agent teams just for specific projects
if you want. So the other thing that you
have to set up if you want that split
pane mode where you can see all the
terminals at the exact same time is you
need to install either T-Mox or iTerm 2.
These are terminal applications that
support the split pane mode and these
are just the two that are supported by
claude code right now. So if you install
T-Mox which is my recommendation or
iTerm 2 then claude code can leverage
that directly to create those terminals
and you can watch them appear in real
time. We'll see that in a second. It is
really really cool. And so the
instructions is a bit different
depending on your operating system. But
actually in the agent team skill
resource that I have for you I have a
readme that gives you the installation
instructions. So really really easy.
Just keep in mind for Windows you do
need WSL. And so I actually have that.
So I got my Linux subsystem here on
Windows. I'm running on Windows right
now. And so the first thing you have to
do is you have to set that environment
variable. So either like this or in that
settings.json file. So cloud code
experimental agent teams. Boom. There we
go. And so now the next time I go into
claude agent teams is available to me.
So now, just like with sub agents, all
we have to do is tell Claude we want to
use the agent team feature, and it's
going to know exactly what we mean. And
so for a very simple example, I'm going
to send in this request right here. So
I'm asking it to create an agent team to
review my codebase. Similar to the demo
I showed you earlier, that was a lot
longer of a prompt, though. But for
simplicity, I'm just going to say have
one agent focus on security, one on code
quality, and the other on documentation.
Now, we could use sub agents for this as
well, but the collaboration we have
here, even for a simple example like
this, I think is really powerful
because, for example, the review on
security might affect the way that we
see documentation. Like maybe we need to
make sure we document any potential
security issues that exist in the
codebase. I think you get the idea of
how that collaboration even for a
review, but especially for when we're
diving into actually writing code, that
is really, really necessary. And so the
lead agent here, it's going to do its
initial analysis, think about the team
to generate, and then it'll spin those
off. So I'll pause and come back once
we've gotten to that point. So here we
go. Usually the indicator is something
like, let me create the tasks and spawn
all three review agents because it
defines the task list that is shared
between all the agents once they
collaborate. And then in just a second
here, we'll see the first pane spin up
on the right hand side. And then it'll
do all three one by one. And boom, there
we go. We have our security reviewer to
start. And you can see the command that
the lead agent runs. It's just starting
another cloud code session, but it's
passing in the prompt to give it that
context around its role. It is the
security reviewer. And then giving it
the task list and access to manage that
with the other agents. And yeah, a lot
is happening here. a lot of buzz on my
screen but it has started all three
agents now really really quickly and
each one of them is focused on their
individual task but they'll start
communicating with each other. Now one
thing that I will say is you have to
watch the logs very very closely just to
get a sense for when the agents are
actually talking to each other. So maybe
that's one of the gripes that I have
with agent teams right now is there's
really not that much visibility into the
actual collaboration. And so I have seen
examples as I've been testing things.
And if you ask the lead agent after how
the agents collaborated, it will give
you a good answer, but for a lot of it,
I just feel like I'm trusting that the
agents really are working on the task
list together. There's not a really good
way to dive into it. Now, one thing you
can do is you can press CtrlB and then
you can press an arrow key to navigate
between the different T-Mox terminals.
And so I can chat with any one of the
agents here to ask it like what are you
currently working on? How are you
collaborating with this agent? It's also
really powerful to go to the primary
agent ask that as well. It give me a
status update on the task list and what
the agents are working on. And then by
the way once all of the agents in the
team are done the lead agent will spin
down all those terminals and you're
brought back to the simple view here
where you can continue to work with the
primary cloud code agent or spin up
another team if you want. So, I want to
take a little bit of a different break
from the video than I usually do. I'm
speaking at an event this March, which I
am super excited to tell you about. It
is the Sonar Summit, which is Sonar's
first ever global virtual event. And I'm
doing a fireside chat on building self-
validation and guardrails into AI coding
systems. And this has been a big focus
of mine because here's the thing, AI is
already writing 30 to 40% of new code at
major tech companies. So, adoption is
pretty much universal. But teams are
realizing that shipping code faster does
not necessarily mean also shipping
quality faster. Review times are
climbing, incidents are up, and security
vulnerabilities just slip through. So
for my session, I'll be covering what I
call the AI validation pyramid. This is
a framework that allows us to define the
validation requirements before we even
write a single line of code. So it's a
part of our plan. And we have our agent
handle the foundation, all the easy
things like the type checking and
linting and our initial round of
testing. And then we as the humans
control the layers that matter most. And
besides my event, there is a lot more
going on at the Sonar Summit. There are
four tracks in total with keynotes on
the future of software development in
the AI era, deep dives into Sonar Cube,
sessions on integrating code quality
into CI/CD pipelines, a lot of awesome
events to attend. And by the way, it's
free to come to Sonar Summit and they
are running this virtual event in pretty
much every single time zone. And so if
you want to know how to ship quality at
speed, not just code at speed, I would
highly recommend checking it out and I
will have a link in the description. So
hopefully the value of agent teams and
how to run them is clear to you. Now I
want to talk about how they are
different from sub aents. And this is a
really important distinction because now
whenever you want to do parallel work
with claude code, you have to make that
decision. Should I ask Claude to use sub
agents or should I ask Claude to spin up
an agent team? And spoiler, there still
are a lot of times where you want to use
sub agents instead, especially because
of a couple of problems with agent teams
that I'll talk about that'll lead really
nicely into the skill that I have built
for you. This makes Claude a lot better
at using agent teams. So, I'm really
excited to show you this, but first,
let's talk about sub aents. So, the
primary idea with sub agents is context
isolation. We want some way to be able
to dish out a request that could take
tens or even hundreds of thousands of
tokens, but all we need back is a
summary. So, our primary agent knows
generally what happened, but it doesn't
have to be polluted by the context of
the entire task. And this is important
because context is the most precious
resource when you're using an AI coding
assistant. But this context isolation
has downsides to it because there is no
coordination between sub aents and the
entire process is just a black box
because it is only the summary, the
final output that is given back to our
primary agent. And so that is why I say
that sub aents are generally used for
focused tasks usually something like
research because all we care about is
the result that summary at the end of
the research. If we're doing something
like coding and we have a sub agent
actually write code then we don't have
any idea into the process of the sub
aent and so the main agent loses a lot
of context as to what was actually
implemented which is why I say research
over implementation. There's no
coordination at all. These sub agents
work completely in isolation, which does
make them very token efficient because
they're honed in on a single task and
they're only communicating a little bit
back to the primary agent. But sometimes
you need a lot more than that. Sometimes
you need your agents to coordinate with
each other, manage a task list together,
and that is where agent teams comes in.
With agent teams, we still have a
primary agent spinning off these
subprocesses, but the difference here is
they're actually talking to each other.
So, they have this shared task list.
They're updating each other on their
progress, communicating to the main
agent as well. And you can instruct
Cloud Code in a lot of different ways
how this communication actually takes
place. We'll talk about that in a little
bit. So, we have true peer-to-peer
coordination. And this is so powerful
for implementation because for example,
our back-end agent might change
something in an API endpoint where it
would have to tell the front-end agent,
hey, I changed this API. Make sure you
update the front-end component that uses
the API as well. And it can actually do
that. When we had sub agents in the past
doing that kind of implementation, those
kinds of things would break all the time
because they're not talking to each
other. So, they'd step on each other's
toes, but not know they're doing so. And
so it was up to the main agent after to
find all those bugs and fix it. And it
was just a complete mess. And so agent
teams is a lot better for
implementation. But you have to keep in
mind that sub agents are a lot more
token efficient. It takes a lot of
tokens to set up this task list,
maintain that collaboration and the
communication between the lead agent and
all of the other agents in the team. And
so this is a really really rough
estimate but yeah often times when
you're using agent teams it's like two
to four times the token usage compared
to just using cloud code by itself or
using sub aents and so you oftentimes
need the collaboration for coding. So
generally I would say if you want a
really simple rule of thumb right now
you should use sub aents for any kind of
research like diving into a codebase or
searching the web and then you should
use agent teams for your actual
implementation. And so a lot of times
when you're working with a single
conversation of cloud code, you might
start with sub agent research like
analyzing the codebase and then create
that task list and spin up the agent
team to knock out the plan that you
created from the research. So again,
it's sub agents for research, feed that
into a plan, and then send that plan
into an agent team. Now, as powerful as
Asian teams are, there are two more
issues that I want to talk about with
you and then we'll get into the template
where I've been starting to address this
and experiment with some things to make
Asian teams more reliable. So, the first
problem that I've encountered as I've
done a lot of testing on both Linux and
Mac is that a lot of times you have to
be very specific with Claude. Like you
have to say, create an agent team with
four teammates to do this and this and
this. If you aren't really specific, it
just kind of hallucinates. It'll make
weird teams. Sometimes it doesn't
understand how to handle the T-Mux
terminals. Most of the time it will
work. But there's just those odd
instances I ran into where it just
totally fell flat on its face. And then
the other problem that I've encountered
is sometimes even with the agents
communicating with each other, they
can't truly run in parallel. For
example, I had it happen once where I
had my database and backend agent run at
the same time. the database agent
defined a bunch of the schema and then
by the time it told the backend agent
what the schema actually was, the
backend agent almost was done with its
work. So it created this entire backend
based on a completely incorrect schema.
So it had to go back and do a lot of
work. And so yes, the communication was
there for it to fix itself, but it would
have been a lot more token efficient if
we just did database agent first, then
the backend agent. And so I have been
working hard through a lot of
experimentation to address both of these
things with the skill that I of course
will have links in the description. This
is giving instructions for cloud code on
how to more reliably create agent teams
and manage the issue of sometimes things
can't be totally parallel and being
really specific for how to use the
terminals and how to create good teams.
And so I have this clone locally ready
to go to create a brand new project. And
by the way, you can use this skill, and
I'll show you how to in a little bit, to
create brand new projects or features in
existing code bases. And so everything
is driven from these instructions here,
which I'm not going to get too in the
weeds with this right now, but
essentially all we have to do is give it
a plan, something we've created with sub
aent research or whatever. Like here's
the next feature we want to build. So we
give it the plan, and then it'll use
these instructions to figure out what's
the optimal team to address this plan.
Should we create a backend front end and
database agent for the team? Like what
should it be? Also giving instructions
for how to manage the terminals
effectively to reduce some of those
hallucinations. And then most
importantly, I have this process called
contract first spawning. So we're not
doing everything in parallel. We we're
setting the stage up front for some of
that work that has to be done before we
can just kick off all the agents like
here's our database schema for example.
Then we send the agents to work in
parallel. And this has gotten very
reliable results for me versus just
telling Claude, "Spin up an Asian team
to do XYZ" without any additional
instructions. And running this is super
easy. So, all you have to do is follow
the instructions in the readme. And like
I showed earlier, I even have
instructions for how to install T-Mux
and then enable the experimental
feature. Copy this into the skills
directory, either global or for your
project. And then that'll give you the
command. And so you can run /build with
agent team. You give it the path to the
plan that you've created already and
then you can define the number of agents
for the team or also let cloud code
figure that out based on your plan. So
it can be very very dynamic. So I have
an example here in my team terminal. I
pointed it to a plan for a brand new
project. So I'm starting something from
scratch and I'm going to have a team of
three agents. And so I'll send this in
and it'll look very similar to the demo
that I showed you earlier for the code
review, but this one's a lot more
intricate. We're building an entire
project. It has to think quite deeply
about the agent team that it'll create.
And we'll see it spin that up in a
little bit here. All right. So, take a
look at this. It's a fresh project and
it's defined the contract chain. So, we
need things to be set up at least partly
in the database before we can even go to
the back end. And then same thing with
backend before we go to the front end.
So, it made the decision here. This is
all dynamic just based on the
instructions I gave it to spawn the
database agent first. So, it's the most
upstream in the contract chain. So its
first job, oh I lost that there. Its
first job is to build the database layer
and then send me its contract. So it
doesn't have to be done done. It just
has to send the contract, then it can
spin up the backend agent. So we're
still going to have some parallel work,
but there's a little bit of the
groundwork it has to lay first. And
there we go. The database agent sent the
contract back to the lead agent. So the
groundwork was done. The lead agent knew
that. And so it started the back-end
agent as well. And then I kicked off
another request. So the database agent
keeps working actually. And so we're
seeing this all happen in parallel
still, but we had a much smarter flow.
And so we'll see the front end start in
a bit as well. I'm not going to show
this full example here because the point
more is to show the intelligence up
front. And I really encourage you to try
this command for yourself. Just see the
consistency for creating these teams
based on the plans, managing the
terminals. It's so powerful once you
have a bit of instruction to claw code
for how you specifically want to use
agent teams. So, I'd also encourage you
to adjust the skill and the command as
you're using it. Make it mold to your
use case and how you want to work with
these teams because there's a lot of
customization that you can do for the
specific coordination as well. Like I'm
doing this contract first approach. You
can do whatever your heart desires. So,
that my friend is all that I got for you
right now on the new agent team feature.
Super powerful stuff. Like I said at the
start of the video, I really feel like I
am peering into the future of agentic
development. But like we've talked
about, it is far from perfect right now.
And so I'll definitely be covering it in
the future as anthropic continues to
improve it once it's beyond the
experimental feature and also once I
work on the skill and continue to use
agent teams better and better. And so if
you appreciate this video and you're
looking forward to more things on agent
teams and agent coding, I would really
appreciate a like and a subscribe. And
with that, I will see you in the next